Dral Alexey (surname, firstname) Founder, CEO and Chief Scientist.

Summary

I am the Chief Scientist at blockchain startup (private), Founder and CEO of BigData Team. BigData Team provides 3 types of services: online course development, in-campus course development and BigData & Machine Learning research, development and consultations. Our partners are the market leaders. For instance:

phone number: +7 920 655 1027

e-mail: <u>aadral@gmail.com</u>

- Yandex the biggest Russian search engine company. We collaborate on online course development. See "<u>Big Data for Data Engineers</u>" Coursera specialization.
- One of the biggest Russian pharmacy company (private). We collaborate on chatbot development.

10 year working experience for the top Russian and international companies, including Amazon AWS, Yandex, Sberbank, Rambler and qualification on large-scale problems, leading R&D teams, defining strategy for the whole departments build up a great mentor with an aspiration to offer insights to my students. Therefore, I teach around the globe, launch new onsite and online courses to reduce the gap between industry and academia, supervise Data Science and Data Engineering initiatives. I am the Senior Lecturer and the Head of Big Data and Machine Learning at Moscow Institute of Physics and Technologies (MIPT).

Major conferences 2017-2018

- 2018, Global Business Insight & Analytics Forum, "Understanding Traditional, Big Data and Emerging Analytical Achitectures"
- 2018, OpenTalks, Higher IT Education: The Challenge
- 2017, Sberbank Corporate University, Ministry for Development of Russian Far East, Workshop on Data Science
- 2017, Sberbank Corporate University, Press Weekend, Workshop on Data Science
- 2017, The Second International Conference "More Than Just Learning", "Soft and Digital Skills Learning: In Search of a Balance"
- 2017, World Festival of Youth and Students, Data Science Secrets
- 2017, Harbour.Space ACM ICPC Workshops, Workshop on BigData

Education

[2016] Certified Scrum Master

[2010-2012] YSDA, MSc., Computer Science, https://yandexdataschool.com/about [2005-2010] MSU, Specialias (cum laude), Mathematics, https://www.msu.ru/en/

Work experience

BigData Team	Founder
December 2016 -	- Attract investors to develop and launch online courses
Present	- Create business plan / calendar plan
	- Lead the team of highly-qualified professionals in the field of
	software development (Big Data and Machine Learning)
	- Head of "Big Data for Data Engineers" Coursera
	specialization (authored by Yandex)

Г	
APT DIHT ¹ MIPT February 2014 - Present	Head of BigData and Machine Learning / Senior Lecturer - responsible for courses on BigData and Machine Learning for BSc. and MSc. students (educate over 400 students / year)
Corporate University Sberbank September 2017 - March 2018	Head of Data Science School - Responsible for IT courses and educational initiatives (Big Data, Data Science / Engineering/ Governance) - Launched internal Machine Learning course Launched series of lectures on practical data analysis with the best Russian IT-specialists (RetailRocket, Rambler, Teradata, Yandex)
PAMCS ² MIPT November 2016 - September 2017	Deputy Director of Research and Innovations - Attract industrial companies to outsource research to phystech-school laboratories - Review existing and develop new IT courses and educational initiatives (e.g. online programs) - Helped to launch R&D laboratory MIPT-Sberbank (responsible for business proposal and budgeting)
Amazon Web Services January 2015 - October 2016	Software Engineer - Develop Frameworks for network automation. Support Customers (30+ teams) across the 24h time zone (e.g. Sydney, Dublin, Seattle). Got award (from VP-level) for internal network automation framework development Negotiate software requirements with vendors Author of a code-free automation tool for Network Engineers - Reduce release time from days to hours by introducing continuous deployment - Development Mentor, author of internal Python course
Yandex November 2013 - November 2014	Senior SDE / Team Lead - E-commerce Recommender Systems development (algorithms, architecture, prototypes and production versions). In particular, I was responsible for up-sales and cross-sales increase at Yandex.Market. Yandex.Market has 1+ million visitors per day and 50+ million of unique items. I have increased CTR by +5+30% and revenue by 10% (depends on recommendation block) I have built Recommender System engine and launched the first online experiment within 2 months.
2007 - 2013	R&D positions at ABBYY, Rambler, Yandex,

¹ DIHT = Department of Innovation and High Technology; ² PAMCS = Phystech-school of Applied Mathematics and Computer Science